<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ara dev</title>
    <description>Write your site description here. It will be used as your sites meta description as well!</description>
    <link>http://www.aracrown.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.aracrown.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 10:36:02 +0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 10:36:02 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Java EE application configuration using Aeonbits Owner</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Every (almost) Java EE based application needs configuration — local, test or production — it does not matter. What matters — how easily this configuration solution is maintained and how easily the environment may be changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to achieve the requirement, however in this blog I will cover one of possible CDI based configuration solutions — Owner by http://owner.aeonbits.org/.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually there are several stages when properties used in production:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hardcoded properties (usually done by novice programmers, otherwise I would treat such properties as constants);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Properties file inside application war file (different properties configured during build time. It is not correct, because the same build cannot be deployed on different environments);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Properties file stored in server file system (properties are independent from war and is environment specific).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java EE lacks easy configuration functionality. There are many discussions related to this topic (HOW TO CONFIGURE JAVA EE 6+ APPLICATIONS …WITHOUT XML, Stack Overflow,Configure Java EE applications or “Putting Bien into practice” and more others), however they need custom actions to take into account:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to manage property injection yourself;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to use Spring framework, which has flexible configuration management mechanism. But do you need Spring only for property loading? I believe — no ☺&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.aracrown.org/2015/05/01/Java%20EE-application-configuration-using-Aeonbits-Owner/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.aracrown.org/2015/05/01/Java%20EE-application-configuration-using-Aeonbits-Owner/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
